Alexander Legeyda

 $\frac{alex@legeyda.com \cdot https://legeyda.com/}{https://github.com/legeyda} \cdot \frac{https://bitbucket.org/legeyda}{https://github.com/legeyda}$

Developer with experience in creating complex systems on the Java platform in banking sector (document flow, integration, performance, security): understanding the architecture of web projects (http internals, servlet, security), experience with high load, understanding of unit testing (junit, mockito), familiarity with relational databases (jdbc), experience with queues (activemq), understanding of the development process and roles in the team (agile, sprints), technical English, professional certificates.

Work experience

C 09.2016 (3 years) iSimpleLab

Lead Java Developer

Led development efforts for remote banking service (b2b, 50000 users) for a large bank:

- Built and guided a development team of three (time estimation, technical statement, code review);
- Carried out diagnostics (analysis of javamelody metrics, jvm dumps) and performance
 optimization (sql-optimization, multithreading issues, java and database cluster debugging) of
 the system while increasing the load during the migration of users from legacy system;
- Increased coverage of legacy code with unit and integration tests (junit, mockito);

09.2012—09.2016 (4 years) Technosery Consulting Java Developer

Participated in development and support of a system for a large bank:

- Implemented a reporting subsystem for corporate underwriting system working under load of 4000 concurrent users (jasperreports, jdbc, warehouse IBM FileNet and Oracle DBMS, GWT).
- Developed algorithms, java-implementation of calculationg of credit conditions in front-office (GWT, JDBC, XSL-FO).
- Configured and administered a bunch of linux-servers for testing purpose (IBM FileNet, Oracle DBMS, LDAP).

11.2011—09.2012 (11 months) Russian Standard Bank

SQL Developer

C++ Developer

Prepared reports on the regular and ad-hoc basis using Oracle data warehouse, query optimiztion, temporary data design.

- Automated execution and delivery of daily reports, which had been performed manually before;
- Configured a regular statistics collection on tables of warehouse, so improved work of department of analytics.

11.2009—11.2011

(2 years) <u>НИИ «Точных</u> <u>Приборов»</u>

Solved a mathematical problem of positioning for GLONASS in a situation of incomplete satellite set, implemented a prototype in C++.

12.2008—11.2011

12.2008—11.2011 (3 vears)

<u>Центр Маркетинга</u>

12.2007—01.2009

12.2007—01.200 (1 year)

(1 year) <u>Prognoz</u>

Developer, System Administrator

Developed multiuser inventory control system (PHP, Zend Framework, MySql); administered LAMP-server.

Mathematician

As part of a research group, designed general equilibrium model (https://legeyda.com/euro-gem.pdf) of economics of European Union, Russia, China; implemented prototype in MATLAB, found numerical solution of large-scale optimization problems.

Education

- Economist-Mathematician, State university of Management, Moscow, 2010
 (papers: https://legeyda.com/chuev/lt.html, https://legeyda.com/lt.pdf)
- Marketing specialist, NIMA Program, Moscow, 2010

Certificaton

- Zend PHP 5.3 Certified Engineer (Zend Technologies)
- Java SE 6 Certified Professional (Oracle)
- Test Deutsch als Fremdsprache (TestDaf Institut)

Keywords

java, oop, solid, rdbms; javaee, servlet, jdbc, spring, javamelody, junit, mockito; tomcat, websphere, wsadmin, activemq; linux, docker, bash, python; javascript, php; rust; maven, gradle, groovy; gwt, zk, xml; git.

Александр Легейда

alex@legeyda.com · https://legeyda.com/ · https://www.linkedin.com/in/legeyda/ https://github.com/legeyda · https://bitbucket.org/legeyda

Разработчик с опытом создания комплексных систем на платформе Java в банковской сфере (документооборот, интеграции, производительность, безопасность): понимание архитектуры web-проектов (внутренности HTTP, servlet, безопасность), опыт работы с высокой нагрузкой, понимание модульного тестирования (junit, mockito), знакомство с реляционными БД (jdbc), опыт работы с очередями (activemq), понимание процесса разработки и ролей в команде (agile, спринты), технический английский, профессиональные сертификаты.

Профессиональный опыт

С 09.2016 (3 года) *iSimpleLab*

Руководитель группы Java-разработки

Участвовал в разработке и поддержке системы дистанционного банковского обслуживания юридических лиц (50000 пользователей) для крупного банка:

- Сформировал и осуществлял руководство группой разработки из трёх человек (оценка сроков, техническая постановка, код-ревью);
- Осуществил диагностику (анализ метрик javamelody, дампов jvm) и оптимизацию производительности (оптимизация sql, решение проблем многопоточности java и БД, отладка кластера) системы во время повышения нагрузки в процессе миграции пользователей со старой системы;
- Увеличил покрытие унаследованного кода модульными и интеграционными тестами (junit, mockito).

09.2012-09.2016 (4 года)

Разработчик Java

Участвовал в разработке и поддержке систем для крупного банка:

<u>Техносерв Консалтинг</u> Реализовал подсистему формирования отчётов для системы документооборота, обслуживающую 4000 пользователей (jasperreports, jdbc, хранилище IBM FileNet и СУБД Oracle, GWT).

- Реализовал вычислительную часть системы онлайн-заявок на кредит для физических лиц (xsl-fo):
- Настроил и поддерживал несколько тестовых linux-стендов со сложной конфигурацией (IBM FileNet, Oracle DBMS, LDAP).

11.2011—09.2012

Разработчик SQL

(11 месяцев) Готовил регулярные отчёты и разовые выгрузки из хранилища данных СУБД Oracle, <u>Банк Русский Стандарт</u> оптимизировал запросы, проектировал таблицы с промежуточными данными.

- автоматизировал формирование и выгрузку ежедневной отчётности, до этого запускаемую в ручном режиме;
- настроил регулярный сбор статистики по таблицам хранилища, позволивший повысить оперативность работы департамента аналитики.

11.2009—11.2011

(2 *года*)

НИИ Точных Приборов

Инженер-программист С++

Решил математическую задачу позиционирования в системе ГЛОНАСС в условиях неполной группировки космических аппаратов, а также реализовал прототип на С++.

Разработал и поддерживал многопользовательскую систему складского учёта (PHP, Zend

12.2008—11.2011

12.2007—01.2009

(3 года)

(1 cod)

Прогноз

<u>Центр Маркетинга</u>

Framework, MySql). Администрировал LAMP-сервер. Математик

В составе исследовательской группы, разработал макроэкономическую модель (https://legeyda.com/euro-gem.pdf) хозяйств Евросоюза, России, Китая и реализовал прототип

на МАТLAB, применив методы численного решения задач оптимизации большой

размерности.

Образование

Математик-экономист, Государственный Университет Управления, 2010 (публикации: https://legeyda.com/chuev/lt.html, https://legeyda.com/conles.pdf, https://legeyda.com/lt.pdf)

Разработчик, системный администратор

Маркетолог, российско-голландской программа "Маркетинговое образование в России", 2010

Сертификаты

- Zend PHP 5.3 Certified Engineer (Zend Technologies)
- Java SE 6 Certified Professional (Oracle)
- Test Deutsch als Fremdsprache (TestDaf Institut)

Ключевые слова

java, oop, solid, rdbms; javaee, servlet, jdbc, spring, javamelody, junit, mockito; tomcat, websphere, wsadmin, activemq; linux, docker, bash, python; javascript, php; rust; maven, gradle, groovy; gwt, zk, xml; git.